Adaline Pendleton Satterthwaite papers SSC.MS.00519
Sophia Smith Collection
- Writings, 1958-2000; 2.25 linear feet
  This series consists of diaries and writings by Satterthwaite and others. The diaries are filed chronologically. Those written while she was employed by the Population Council (1966-1974) take the form of daily typed reports that describe in detail her activities. Subsequent handwritten diaries describe her career with other international organizations and her life after retirement (1974 - 1994).
- Professional Activities, 1958-2000; 4.75 linear feet
  This series consists of three sub-series: Medical missionary work is relatively small and primarily contains printed materials about China. Maternal and child health, and family planning is the largest sub-series and contains much of the raw data generated by Satterthwaite and her colleagues. It is arranged alphabetically by name of organization. Post-retirement work documents Satterthwaite's work as a board member of the Child Health Foundation, the Institute for Development Training (in partnership with Reformed Churches of America), and Planned Parenthood of Buck's County.
- Subject Files, 1956-2000; 1.75 linear feet
  This series consists of mixed materials that are filed alphabetically by subject. It illustrates the breadth and depth of Satterthwaite's life-long interest in and commitment to population control, maternal and child health, human rights, and peace and nuclear disarmament.